A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Apprenticeship Council, 1938-2023
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Apprenticeship Council, 1780-1906
The Library of Virginia
54197
6.25 cu. ft. (17 boxes)
Virginia Apprenticeship Council
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession 54197 transferred by the Virginia Dept. of Labor and Industry, xx-xx.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Apprenticeship Council, established by the Virginia General Assembly (§2.2-2044), sets standards for apprentice agreements in the Commonwealth of Virginia. The Apprenticeship Council is authorized to determine standards for apprenticeship agreements; to approve, terminate, or cancel such agreements; to issue certificates of journeymanship; to review decisions of local and state joint apprenticeship committees adjusting disputes; to initiate deregistration proceedings; and to advise the State Board for Community Colleges on policies to coordinate apprenticeship-related instruction delivered by state and local public education agencies. The Council includes eleven members, four representatives from employer and employee organizations respectively with familiarity of apprenticeable occupations are appointed by the Government. The remaining three members of the Council serve as ex-officio members include: Director, Virginia Works (Department of Workforce Development and Advancement); Chancellor of the Virginia Community College System; a local superintendent from a school division that provides apprenticeship related technical instruction. The Virginia Registered Apprenticeship program is an employment training model that produces highly skilled workers to meet the demands of employers competing in a global economy, through a combination of on-the-job training and related technical instruction.
The Virginia Apprenticeship Council fall under the Virginia Dept. of Labor and Industry. The Dept. of Labor and Industry has its origins in the Bureau of Labor and Industrial Statistics, which was created by an act of the General Assembly passed on March 3, 1898. The General Assembly saw a need for an agency to compile and circulate data on the industrial pursuits of the state as they related to the commercial, industrial, social, educational, and sanitary condition of the laboring classes and to the permanent prosperity of the productive industries of the state. The name of the Bureau was changed to the Bureau of Labor and Industry on February 13, 1924.
Several division were added to the bureau to deal with a variety of labor related issues. The Division of Mines and Quarries was created in 1912 (duties of this division transferred to the newly created Dept. of Mines, Minerals and Energy in 1985) and joined the Division of Factory Inspection as a unit with the Bureau. In 1922 The Division of Women and Children was created to enforce child labor laws, the 10 hour work day limit and regulate issues related to the employment of women. The Division of State Public Employment Service was created in 1926 to help connect people seeking jobs and employers seeking workers (this division was eliminated in 1960 with the creation of the Virginia Employment Commission).
The state government reorganization act of April 18, 1927 changed the name of the bureau to the Dept. of Labor and Industry and gave it the status of a regular administrative agency of the state. The governor appoints a commissioner, subject to confirmation by the General Assembly, who exercises supervision and control of the department. Several additional divisions were created in the department: Division of Apprenticeship Training (1938), Division of Factory, Institution and Mercantile Inspection (1951 - in 1967 this becomes the Division of Construction Safety Inspection and the Division of Industrial Safety), Advisory Council on Industrial Safety (1951), Safety Codes Commission (1962 - which later becomes the Safety and Health Codes Board), Division of OSHA Voluntary Compliance and Training (1977), Division of State Labor Law Administration (1978), Bureau of Occupational Health (1985 - transferred from Virginia Dept. of Health).
The Dept. of Labor and Industry's primary responsibility is the administering and enforcing of occupational safety and occupational health activities in both the public and private sectors. The mission of the Dept. is to make Virginia a better place to work by promoting safe and healthful workplaces, best employment practices, and job training opportunities. The Dept. provides Virginians with a broad variety of services to employers and workers that range from workplace safety, assistance to companies in establishing apprenticeships, to collecting unpaid wages for workers.
Scope and Content
Minutes and related attachments documenting the meetings, activities, discussions, policy decisions, and recommendations of the Virginia Apprenticeship Council. Includes official board minutes, as well some committee meeting minutes, agendas and other meeting materials, such as correspondence, briefs, forms, legislation, meeting transcripts, membership lists, newspaper clippings, plans, public hearing transcripts, publications, regulations, reports, resolutions, standards, statistics and talking points. There are no minutes for 1960, 1966-1968, and 1971, and each year may not contain minutes for all council meetings held in that year.
Arrangement
These volumes are arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Minutes of the Virginia Apprenticeship Council, 1938-2023.
  - Minutes, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1986 Jan 16 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1986 June 12 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1986 Oct 23 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1987 Jan 15 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1987 Apr 30 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1987 June 4 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1987 Aug 6 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1987 Nov 5 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 1988 Apr 22 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1988 Sept 15 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1988 Dec 5 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1989 Apr 20 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1989 June 15 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1990 Jan 18 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1990 Apr 19 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1990 Oct 18 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1990 Dec 4 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1991 Feb 7 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 1991 May 16 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1991 Sept 19 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1991 Nov 21 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1992 Mar 30 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1992 Apr 21 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1992 July 16 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1992 Sept 17 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1992 Nov 18 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1993 Mar 25 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1993 Apr 29 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1993 June 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1993 June 28 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1993 Sept 16 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1993 Nov 2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1994 Mar 10 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1994 June 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1994 Sept 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1994 Dec 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1995 Mar 16 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1995 May 25 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1995 Sept 21 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1995 Dec 14 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1996 Mar 21 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1996 May 23 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1996 Sept 19 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1996 Dec 5 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1997 Mar 20 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1997 Mar 20 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1997 May 22 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1997 July 21 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1997 Aug 6 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1997 Sept 18 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1997 Dec 11 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1998 Mar 19 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1998 May 21 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1998 Sept 17 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1998 Dec 10 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1999 Mar 18 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1999 June 17 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1999 July 22 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1999 Oct 21 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1999 Dec 9 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2000 Mar 16 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2000 June 16 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2000 Sept 21 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2000 Dec 14 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2001 Mar 15 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2001 June 14, 21 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2001 Dec 13 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2002 Jan 31 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2002 Mar 21 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2002 June 13 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2002 Oct 17 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2002 Nov 7 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2002 Dec 19 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2003 Mar 20 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2003 June 19 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2003 Oct 23 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2003 Dec 11 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2004 Mar 18 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2004 Apr 26 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2004 June 10 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2004 Sept 16 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2004 Dec 9 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2005 Mar 17 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 2005 June 23 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 2005 Sept 14 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 2005 Dec 8 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 2006 Mar 16 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 2006 June 15 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 2006 Sept 21 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 2006 Dec 14 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 2007 Mar 15 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2007 June 21 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2007 Sept 20 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2007 Dec 13 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2008 Mar 20 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2008 June 19 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2008 Sept 25 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2008 Dec 11 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2009 Mar 19 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2009 June 18 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 2009 Sept 17 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 2009 Dec 10 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 2010 Apr 15 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 2010 Aug 19 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 2010 Nov 18 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 2011 Apr 25 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 2011 Aug 18 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 2012 Mar 22 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 2012 Aug 16 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 2012 Nov 15 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 2013 Apr 4 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2013 Aug 22 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2013 Nov 21 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2014 Mar 13 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2014 June 12 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2014 Sept 18 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2015 Mar 19 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2015 June 18 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2015 Sept 17 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2016 Mar 17 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 2016 June 16 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 2016 Sept 15 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 2017 Mar 16 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 2017 June 22 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 2017 Sept 21 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Minutes, 2018 Mar (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 2018 June 21 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 2018 Sept 20 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 2019 Mar 21 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2019 June 20 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2019 Sept 19 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2020 Mar 19 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2020 Nov 5 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2021 Mar 18 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2021 June 17 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2021 Sept 16 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2022 Mar 31 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2022 June 23 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 2022 Sept 27 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 2023 Mar 30 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 2023 June 29 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 2023 Sept 21 (Box 17, Folder 14)